[waves crashing]
[engine revving]
[knocking on door]
Hey. Sonny. Five minutes.
["Whole Lotta Love" playing]
♪ You need coolin' ♪
[grunts]
♪ Baby. I'm not foolin' ♪
♪ I'm gonna send ya
Back to schoolin' ♪
♪ Way down inside
Honey. you need it ♪
♪ I'm gonna give you my love
I'm gonna give you my love ♪
[people chattering]
♪ Want a whole lotta love
Want a whole lotta love ♪
Sonny! Hey. BMW guys are over there
bitching about brake trouble.
Thanks. Molly. You're a superstar.
I'll see you out there.
♪ All the good times
Baby. baby. I've been yearning ♪
♪ Way. way down inside
Honey. you need it ♪
♪ I'm gonna give you my love ♪
♪ Want a whole lotta love ♪
Turn my back for one minute.
It's all gone to shit. Sonny.
Pat had to ease off.
We've dropped down to seventh.
If you can just hold position overnight.
hopeful sunrise catches us a break.
Sonny. watch that high-speed balance.
High-speed balance.
[drills whirring]
How's the gearbox?
It's holding up. but go easy.
[breathing deeply]
[breathing heavily]
[commentator] The crowds may
have gone home. but the racing continues.
Sonny Hayes back in the Porsche
for Peak Geico Chip Hart Racing.
the midnight shift.
We all know Hayes
likes to light up the night.
but with the BMW at the head of this pack.
he's got a massive job ahead of him.
Right out of the gate.
Hayes threads the needle into turn three.
moving up to fourth place.
Sonny. wanna maybe pass on the straights?
Just let me drive. will ya?
[song continues]
[commentator] Look out.
Engine trouble for the number 12.
That moves Hayes up another spot.
♪ You've been coolin'
Baby. I've been droolin' ♪
Sweet baby Jesus. We got ten more hours.
Just let Sonny do his thing.
And if these first few laps
are any indication.
it appears as though Sonny Hayes
may have left his brake pedal at home.
♪ I'm gonna give you
Every inch of my love ♪
Hayes sets his sights on the BMW.
♪ Yeah. all right. let's go ♪
- [grunts]
- [commentator] And he attacks.
♪ Want a whole lotta love
Want a whole lotta love ♪
[commentator]
Here comes Hayes on the outside.
Come on. Sonny.
♪ Want a whole lotta love ♪
♪ Way down inside ♪
[pants]
♪ Love ♪
♪ My. my. my. my
My. my. my. my ♪
[commentator] The BMW late on the brakes.
He's in the grass.
Can Hayes hang on?
And he does.
Goddamn!
See that? That's how you race. boys.
When you get back in that car.
you need to do the same goddamn thing.
♪ Hey. oh. ooh ♪
[commentator] Sonny Hayes brings it
into pit lane after an epic third stint
that puts Chip Hart Racing out in front.
Now. it's up to Cale Kelso
to hang on to that lead.
[Kelso] Thanks for the head start. Chief.
Hey. Lose that lead. I'll kill ya.
♪ Shake for me. girl
I wanna be your backdoor man ♪
[BMW driver] Hayes!
Hey. dirtbag!
- Gonna run me off the track. Hayes?
- [crew member] It's not worth it.
You think I don't know where to find you?
Screw you!
Let go of me!
♪ Oh. oh. oh ♪
Hey. Attaboy. Sonny.
Thanks. Don't wake me if we lose.
[crowd cheering]
[laughs]
[cheers]
♪ Keep it coolin'. baby ♪
[song fades]
Sonny Hayes.
I believe you forgot something.
Bag's full. Chip.
Seriously?
Your first win at Daytona.
Don't you even want to touch it?
- Ooh. bad luck.
- Come on.
- Just touch it.
- [laughing] No. Hey.
I will take that bonus check though.
Sonny. Sonny! Just hear me out.
Look. I wanna bring you on board.
- [laughs]
- You're CHR family now.
Right here. next year. let's run it back.
We did it. man. Deal's a deal.
I-I know what a deal is.
So that's it? One and done?
I appreciate the seat. Chip. I really do.
What kind of way is that to race?
You just spend your whole life
starting over. man.
You take care.
- [engine starts]
- I'll see you down the road.
Hey! Don't you want the watch?
[Sonny] Got one!
["Round and Round" playing on radio]
[radio presenter 1]
WHOG. Ormond-by-the-Sea.
[radio presenter 2]
Proud to be locally owned.
A Southern Stone station.
The world's most famous rock...
[radio presenter 1] ...from the world's
most famous beach. we are...
[radio presenter 2]
...Daytona's rock station...
[radio presenter 1]
...ninety-five seven. the Hog.
♪ Out on the streets
That's where we'll meet ♪
♪ You make the night
I always cross the line ♪
♪ Tightened our belts
Abused ourselves ♪
♪ Get in our way
We'll put you on your shelf ♪
[timer buzzes]
Sorry. can I use your phone
for a second. please?
It's not working.
Um. no.
You know. you remind me of this friend
I used to have.
Which friend?
Friend who dressed better.
This is a Gucci suit.
So's this.
Huh. What did your friend do?
Drove cars.
- Was he fast?
- Wasn't slow.
- Did he win?
- [inhales sharply] Yeah. he did.
- Come here. you son of a bitch.
- [laughs]
Oh. God.
[friend] Are you thinking Baja?
[Sonny] Yeah. New day. new challenge.
That's exactly what I said to myself
when I bought Apex GP.
- ["The Stroke" playing on radio]
- [groans]
How deep in the hole are you?
I'll tell you.
but you have to promise not to laugh.
Shoot.
350...
million.
Don't laugh.
Impressive.
Well. been fun?
Oh. yeah. Absolutely.
What's the problem then?
Problem is two seasons and a half.
zero points.
My best driver left for another team.
He said the car was a shitbox.
[laughs]
The team is in last place.
My number two's a rookie.
And the season's half over.
- How many races left?
- Nine.
And if we don't turn it around.
I lose the team.
- What?
- Mmm.
But you own the team.
No race wins in your first three seasons.
the board can force a sale.
Man. sounds like you need a new board.
I need a new driver.
[laughs]
[Sonny] You got F2. You got F3.
You got an entire assembly line of kids
raised on the simulator.
No. I don't have time for some kid
to learn how to come in tenth. I don't.
Well. you don't just walk off the street
and pilot a rocket.
Yes. you can if you've done it before.
That's the whole point.
Louis Chiron was 57 years old
when he won the Monaco Grand Prix.
- Louis who?
- Philippe Étancelin. 56 years old.
You just Googled these names. didn't you?
Some people look at Sonny Hayes.
they see a guy who lives in a van.
a gambling junkie who missed his shot.
Wow. Ruben. you are really selling this.
But I see a guy who makes teams better.
- I see experience. I see know-how.
- Mmm.
[laughs] You're off your meds.
My rookie's a phenomenal talent.
Phenomenal. But he's young.
You know what he lacks? Maturity.
You plus him?
Boom. I got a team.
[Sonny]
All right. Let's say I'm the next Louis...
- Chiron. Mm-hmm.
- Him.
The problem is it's not just the driver.
it's the car.
I've followed your season. Ruben.
"Shitbox" is being kind.
I knew you were watching.
What if I told you
we get an upgrade package this weekend?
- Six months in development--
- Ruben...
No. no. no. Wait.
I just need one of my cars
across the finish line first. One.
I love ya. I'm not going back.
[sighs]
Okay.
What would he want you to do?
[chuckles]
[Sonny] Join a boy band?
Seriously. Come on.
Seriously. I'd ask him
what he's smiling about.
Come on.
He's smiling at the possibility.
We both know how that ended.
Yep.
Okay.
- This is a first-class ticket to London.
- Oh. my God.
First class.
I'm offering you
an open seat in Formula 1.
The only place you could say for one day.
if you win.
you are the absolute best in the world.
- Hey. Ruben.
- Mmm.
- Ever seen a miracle?
- Not yet.
Me neither.
Good to see you. amigo.
- All right. sweetie. here you go.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey. let me ask you something.
Close friend of yours made you an offer
that was 100%. positively
too good to be true.
What do you do?
[sighs] Well. how much are we talking?
Not about the money.
So what is it about?
Hmm.
[engine revving]
[driving synth music playing]
[crew member] Tire temps look good.
Eighty-five front. 75 rear.
- You are good to push.
- [driver] Copy.
[crew member] Battery is full.
You're good for strat two.
[driver] Going for a lap.
Purple sector one. Best one yet.
[driver] Car feels good.
[tires squeal]
Damn!
Locked it up. Flat spot. front left.
[sighs]
Bring him in.
Go to strat one.
Uh. box this lap. Box this lap.
- [groans]
- Let's go find those gremlins.
[blows]
[crew chattering]
[groans]
[grunts. gasps]
Sorry. Joshua.
Jodie. try not to kill our driver.
What's the verdict? [sniffs]
[sighs] I don't know what's happening.
I mean. it feels good. I start to push.
Then it understeers in the slow corners
and oversteers the fast.
What? On entries or exits?
Either. Both.
Oh. great. Yeah.
There's 10.000 sensors on this thing
and you can't tell me what's going on.
But I'm not out there. am I?
So. I-I'm gonna need
your help on this. Please.
[speaking German]
[child giggles]
[in English]
150 million dollar jungle gym.
So cute.
We should let her drive.
Can't be any worse.
[child imitating engine]
Joshua.
- Hi.
- Lisbeth. PR?
- Oh. yeah.
- Doesn't matter.
For the press conference.
we want to steer around tech issues
and focus on the super strong bond
with your new teammate. Luca Cortez.
[laughs] Luca?
Who I've known a week.
Who when he was third banana
on the left at Red Bull.
told the press he thought
Joshua Pearce was overrated.
That Luca Cortez?
Yes.
- [chuckles] Can't wait. Yeah.
- All right. Great. Thank you.
- Yo.
- Yep.
That's a yes? Yeah? Yes? [groans]
[Joshua] What's up?
Yo. you were right. bro.
Ruben's in big trouble.
He might have to sell the team.
- [snaps fingers]
- I knew it.
And what does that mean for me?
New buyers. they're likely to clean house.
Listen.
You need to show these people
who the number one driver really is. man.
Now.
Or you're gonna lose your job.
Yeah. Let that sink in.
[speaking German]
- [in English] Hey.
- [parent. speaking German]
You good?
Okay. let's take
the first half of the season
and erase it from our minds.
[crew cheers]
Someone says.
"Kaspar. what happened this year?"
I swear on the lives of my children.
I do not freaking know.
[laughs]
There's only this car.
And there is only our future.
[crew exclaiming] Yes. Our future.
[Kaspar] Who is that asshole?
He's with me.
Your man thought I was maintenance.
Sent me to the back gate.
[Ruben chuckles]
Brother. you have never let me down.
- [chuckles] Well. there's still time.
- [chuckles]
Apex GP!
Sonny Hayes.
He raced with me back in the day.
- Against you. you mean.
- Yeah.
- Kate McKenna. our technical director.
- Hi.
- Dodge Dauda. our chief mechanic.
And Kaspar Smolinski. team principal.
You may know him by reputation.
Five-time Constructors champion
with Ferrari.
Huh.
As a rear jack man.
So was my pop. Can't win without 'em.
- And our talented rookie. Joshua.
- Why has he got a helmet?
- Uh. safety?
- [chuckles]
Joshua. your seat is safe. Okay?
Sonny is here for the audition.
When was the last time you won a race?
Sunday. Daytona.
Oh. I'm sorry. I-I meant Formula 1.
Oh. I'm sorry. Then same as you.
- [laughs. exclaims] Wow.
- [chuckles]
Never thought I'd say this.
has anyone seen Luca Cortez?
- [chuckles]
- Sidebar bitte. Ruben.
When I interview with you.
many veteran drivers--
Yeah. who all turned you down.
- How many?
- Seven.
- That's a lot.
- I'm number seven?
- Mm-hmm.
- You're eight.
This is a disaster.
Starting to feel more like a nine.
Technically. there is one
who I've not heard from yet.
- [stammers]
- So I am a nine?
You know how numbers work. right?
In business.
my most inspired ideas come late.
Yeah. Best things in life
usually arrive ninth. right?
With respect. Ruben. I cannot condone
we spend our only test day
giving your long-lost teammate
an audition.
Kaspar. you misunderstand.
We're not auditioning him.
He's auditioning us.
That's your new driver.
Good luck.
New wing. new side pods.
Any changes to the floor?
Nothing the eight other drivers
wouldn't have figured out.
That's why they call me Lucky Number Nine.
Listen. it's been a while
since you've driven here. mate. Yeah?
The balance on these cars are tricky.
so be careful turn one and nine.
Wouldn't want to see you get hurt.
How about we set a reasonable target?
Give me the same setup as him. If I can't
post a lap time within a second of JP's.
then I will promptly see myself out
and you're free to take a shot
at lucky number ten.
- Ten?
- Ten.
Ten.
Who's JP?
[rock music playing]
Cross round on Brooklands.
easy on Luffield.
Up to Woodcote. hard out in Copse.
And be careful on the curve.
Default mode. settings one. to two.
back to three.
Differential one through four.
DRS.
♪ I bet you thought
You'd seen the last of me ♪
♪ I can't change the way I am. you see ♪
♪ I think it's my responsibility ♪
[exhales deeply]
♪ To tell you
I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
[engine starts. revs]
♪ I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
[breathes deeply]
Okay. Let's see what you got.
If he raced with Ruben.
he raced with Schumacher. With Senna.
♪ I tried changing my reality ♪
♪ But I don't think
It's gonna set me free ♪
♪ There's only one thing I can guarantee ♪
♪ And that's
I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
♪ I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
All right. pull up Joshua's sector times.
Twenty quid says he stacks it.
Make it a hundred. you're on.
Oh. shit.
- [laughs]
Sorry. uh. this is Hugh Nickleby.
your race engineer.
Good morning. Hugh.
How are my tire temps looking?
Yep. almost warm. End of the lap.
you should be good to push.
[exhales deeply]
[grunts]
[tires squeal]
[sighs]
Right. Man.
- [Sonny] Hugh?
- Yes. sir?
- You should've taken that bet.
- [chuckles]
- [sighs]
- [Hugh] Copy that.
♪ No one's accusing me of sanity ♪
♪ I ain't everybody's cup of tea ♪
♪ But that's the facts
I'm talkin' factually ♪
Going for a lap.
♪ I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
♪ Yes. I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
♪ Whoa. I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
♪ I'm just as bad as I used to be ♪
Nope. Shit.
He's dead.
Come on. Don't do that.
[all groan]
And buried.
[grunts]
Wait.
[inhales sharply]
Now.
[grunts]
The car is there. come on.
He's gaining.
Ah. shit.
- [tires squealing]
- [grunts]
[grunts. groans]
[song ends]
- [grunts]
- You okay?
[groans] Yep. All good.
- [laughs]
- [sirens wailing]
[grunting]
- [groans. sighs]
- [Kaspar] Oh!
- [Kate] Come on.
- [Sonny pants]
Yeah. she's got something.
Yeah. you mean had something.
But definitely snappy
in the high-speed corners.
Unpredictable in the lows.
Had trouble with the rears. turns 14. 16--
And the final turn. maybe?
- No. that's on me.
- What was his lap time?
He passed his entirely self-imposed test
by five hundredths of a second.
[sighs] Huh.
[chuckles]
Well... [sighs]
...it's a start.
[scoffs]
[laid-back music playing]
Bro. we got nine races to catch
the eye of another team. you know.
And as your manager. I have to advise you
that we need to start hitting
these social and sponsor events.
You need more engagement. Josh.
more followers.
- All right. deal.
- All right. cool. I'm just saying. innit?
You eaten? I'm starving.
Nah.
Gotta see someone though.
Yeah? Hey. take a picture. post that shit.
Send it to me. I'll post that shit.
It's my mum.
Don't you dare post that shit.
[laughs]
I knew you was gonna say that.
[music ends]
[music plays softly on radio]
[phone chimes]
- [clicks tongue. sighs]
- Okay. baby?
Yeah. Just tired.
Bad tires or the engine?
Come on. Mum.
You don't know about the cars.
[chuckles] Facety.
All right. I may not know much about cars.
but I know a lot about you.
Go.
[sighs]
I might lose my seat
if the team don't win a race.
Any race.
There are other teams?
Yeah. there's 20 seats.
but they're all filled.
Plus. there's this new guy. and... [sighs]
...he's old.
How old?
Like. really old. Like... 80.
[laughs]
He's such an arsehole. Mum.
He's quick. though.
Don't mind that.
Focus on you.
You can spend your whole life
worrying about other people.
but your time is right now.
You still love it?
Course I still love it.
Then remember what
your father used to say.
"Put your head down and drive."
Yes. ma'am.
- [chuckles]
[jaunty music playing]
- [bells ring]
- [cows moo]
[bicycle bell rings]
[herder 1] Come on. then. It's all good.
Come on. Come on. then.
Come on. Come on.
- Come here. Come on. then.
- You're kiddin' me.
[herders clamoring]
[herder 2] Don't park there.
It's just a car. Quieten down.
Come on. eh? Come on.
[music ends]
Thought your job was to build
the fastest car on the planet.
[chuckles] My job is wind.
So. helps to feel it.
Mmm. [sighs]
["Bright Lights" playing]
Mysterious moves at Apex GP.
who have finally announced the driver
who will take their second seat.
And in a bizarre twist.
it's American Sonny Hayes.
who hasn't raced in Formula 1
for over three decades.
Son of an IndyCar mechanic.
Hayes was considered something
of a reckless young phenomenon.
the greatest who never was.
His former career
being brought to an abrupt halt
by a horrific accident
at the Spanish Grand Prix.
He reappeared a decade later
in racing championships
as diverse as Le Mans.
NASCAR. the Dakar Rally.
and even a stint as
a New York taxi driver.
- Oh. no.
- [crowd applauding]
[Will Buxton] But now he's back
racing for a team which has.
in its entire F1 history.
never even finished in the top ten.
None of this will dampen speculation
that majority shareholder Cervantes
Capital are looking to sell the team.
And if they do.
that will likely also bring an end
to the career of F1 rookie Joshua Pearce.
- Can we go now?
- "Desperate times." they say.
"call for desperate measures."
but I honestly cannot recall
a driver signing
- quite as desperate as this.
- Let's go.
Boy. look at my son.
- [Joshua] Huh? [chuckles]
- Hey. [laughs]
- [manager] That's the one.
- [Joshua's mom] Huh.
- [music ends]
- That's the other driver?
Yep. That's him and his stupid face.
But. wait. you said he was old.
He not that old.
[manager] Hey. Josh.
You want a next shot anywhere?
Nine races means nine times
you have to beat Chuck Norris.
For now. start by winning over the press.
- Yeah? You ready?
- Mm-hmm.
Cool. Let's go.
- [sighs]
- Mmm.
That's a handsome man right there.
[chuckles]
[Will Buxton] Joshua. Hey. Um. it's been
an undeniably messy start to your season.
No wins. car problems throughout.
and now you have another new teammate.
How exactly are you finding it?
Messy start doesn't mean
you can't finish neat. All right?
Apex have a fire crew of engineers.
so I'm confident we'll come back fightin'.
In terms of new teammates.
I think it's really wonderful that Apex
are giving second chances to the elderly.
[all laugh]
Ah. yes. Next question.
Thank you. Yes. Don. Yeah.
Mr. Hayes. Hi. Don Cavendish.
Um. welcome back to the UK.
It's been a while. mmm?
I mean. last time
you raced at Silverstone.
Bill Clinton was your president.
and we were all dancing the Macarena.
- So. uh. it must be surreal to be back.
- [reporters laugh]
Yeah.
And. uh. during that decade.
you gave up racing.
and. uh. gambled professionally?
Uh-huh.
Before declaring yourself
personally bankrupt?
Yep.
[Don] You had a marriage annulled
and two more ended in divorce?
Yep.
Anything you wish you'd done differently?
Yeah.
[reporters murmuring]
[chuckles] No more questions.
Thank you. Yes. Thank you.
[reporters clamoring]
[somber orchestral music playing]
[grunts]
[music becomes electronic. dramatic]
[panting]
[breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[sighs]
[people chattering]
[Joshua] Yes. Dodge.
What time was he here?
Before me.
- And before you.
- [Joshua sighs]
[music fades]
[people cheering]
[ball bouncing in distance]
[sighs]
Okay. here he comes. Apologize.
[scoffs] Apologize? I can't do that.
- How you mean? Why not?
- Because it's a sign of weakness.
It's a sign of strength.
Sign of weakness.
You hard ears. just do it.
Mum. I can't.
You can. You will.
[sighs]
[sucks teeth]
Hey. man.
Other day at the press conference.
stuff I said wasn't cool.
[muttering] You say sorry.
So. basically what I'm trying to say is...
I'm sorry.
It's all right. You're just worried I'm
quicker than you. Hi. I'm Sonny.
Oh. Bernadette Pearce. Nice to meet you.
Pleasure.
It's all good. I'll see you out there.
[scoffs]
[ball bouncing]
[pop song playing. muffled]
[sighs]
[sighs] How are you feeling?
- So good.
- Good.
- You good?
Good.
No pressure.
None.
[sighs]
- Great.
- Great. [clears throat]
Great.
[Croft] Welcome along to Silverstone.
the circuit where on the 13th of May 1950
the Formula 1 World Championship began.
Today. we kick off the final nine races
of this thrilling championship season
here at the 77th British Grand Prix.
[Brundle] As always.
11 teams will take the grid.
fielding two drivers each.
With race order determined
by the qualifying times set yesterday.
Red Bull will start on pole
followed by the two McLarens
and two Ferraris.
[Croft] Drivers.
two minutes to national anthem.
["God Save the King" playing]
[marching band playing]
["We Will Rock You" playing]
Sonny!
Ah. Ruben.
Don't make me talk to the money.
Come on. give me a moment.
Just smile and shake hands.
He's an important member of the board.
Sonny. this is Peter Banning.
- one of my investors.
- Hi.
Hi.
He knows absolutely nothing about racing...
- Yeah.
- ...but he's my eyes and ears on the board.
And. uh. you're Ruben's Hail Mary.
Now. that is
an American football term. right?
The Hail Mary. the long shot. The--
I believe it's a religious term. originally.
That is true. That is true.
I'm praying to them all.
I'm the one guy on the board
who actually wants to keep the team.
The rest are calling it. you know.
Ruben's Inferno.
But. seriously. man. I'm hooked.
I've binged all of Drive to Survive.
I honestly don't think I've ever known
so much about car tires. It's incredible.
I'm gonna get back to my day job.
- Okay.
["We Will Rock You" continues]
Hey. man.
We're counting on you. Good luck.
What are you doing here. Sonny?
[Croft] And as the clock ticks then
to the top of the hour.
it's time to get things going here
at Silverstone.
It's formation lap first.
One tour of the track and a chance for the
drivers to warm up their tires and brakes.
[Brundle] Oh. no.
There's a problem for Apex.
That's Hayes in P22. His car hasn't moved.
Hang on. I got power trouble.
It's start mode. Sonny.
Start mode on.
[Brundle] Yes.
a lesson for everyone at home.
New car? Do read the manual.
[Croft] It's been a while since he was
out on the track. At this rate...
- Dios mío.
- ...he's not even gonna get into the race.
Ay.
- I got it.
- [engine revs]
All good.
[Croft] And he's away at last.
Thank goodness for that.
[Brundle] If he falls too far behind
on the formation lap...
- Drink?
- ...he'll be at risk...
- Eh? No.
- ...of having to start in the pit lane.
Where's Sonny? He's holding us up.
Yeah. Just checking. Joshua.
Just checking.
- What's wrong with his car?
- What? Nothing.
[Brundle] With a clear track ahead.
Hayes has been able
to push much harder on this formation lap.
He'll turn up at the back of the grid
with warm tires. ready to go.
Cheeky shit. It's on purpose.
What is this guy doing?
[Croft] This is actually now
turning into an advantage for Sonny Hayes.
[Brundle] And he's just made it in time.
Watch out for his start.
[Croft] Five lights ahead of the drivers.
It's lights out and away we go!
[crowd cheering]
Here comes Sonny Hayes.
ladies and gentlemen.
Using those warm tires to carve his way
through the back of the field.
[Brundle] And if you ever need
confidence in your car.
it's here at Silverstone.
Hayes is just sailing past people.
He's moved up seven places
since the start.
- Apex GP has struggled with this car...
- Yes!
...but they've brought an upgrade package
this weekend.
Let's see if it makes a difference
as Hayes attacks Perez in the Red Bull.
Car's bouncing around this dirty air.
I can't position to attack.
[Brundle] Hayes complaining
about his car over the radio.
That's not what the team wants to hear.
Copy. Gap is 0.9 to Perez.
You're within DRS range.
Should be able to take him
on the next straight.
[Croft] Hayes now using
the drag reduction system to get past.
- [cheering]
- Yeah!
Won't be able to hold him off. guys.
I got no grip.
- This is trouble now for Apex GP.
- Oh. come on.
The Red Bull's tires are now warm
and Hayes hasn't got his tire advantage
from the start anymore.
We've seen the attack.
Now it's all about defense.
And Perez on the attack into Vale.
Hayes is in trouble.
This could be the places reversed.
- [crowd cheering]
- And it is.
Damn.
Rear end is loose.
Tell me if you see a fix.
Tell him to pull back the entry
to get a better exit.
He-He thinks it's the setup. It's not.
[Croft] Twenty laps down.
Verstappen leads but Joshua Pearce
is struggling out there at the moment.
Guys. get me off these softs.
I'm going backwards.
Copy that. Lap 20. Box. box.
[Brundle] Stakes couldn't be higher
for rookie Joshua Pearce.
This is not where you want to be.
in last place.
[groans] I'm jammed. Back up!
Hit something. What was that?
[crowd shrieks]
[Croft] Ooh. a seven-second pit stop.
Apex GP won't be happy with that.
That's double the time it should've taken.
Lost the rears. Box. box.
Copy. Go to plan B. Box. box.
[Croft] And here comes Sonny Hayes
for a fresh set of tires.
He'll be hoping these will help him
hold on to his current position of P15.
Front jacks! Front jacks!
[Brundle] The front jack has
not worked properly.
- You're kidding me.
- This is causing absolute pandemonium
in the Apex GP pit lane.
Whatever could go wrong
is going wrong for this team.
[Croft] And coming out of the pit.
Hayes just ahead of his teammate.
As Pearce and Hayes go battling it out
here at Silverstone.
Coming for you. old man.
Got the pace. man.
Tell him to let me pass.
Yeah. Copy. Hold position. Stand by. Kate.
Josh is faster. Sonny is on cold tires.
Yeah. okay. Sonny. no fighting.
Let him through.
Sonny. no fighting.
Who's fighting? I'm racing.
[Croft] Pearce on the inside.
Hayes on the outside.
[Brundle] Hayes trying
to make him eat concrete
up against the old pit wall there.
Joshua. you're gonna
have to fight for position.
You are racing Sonny.
A-ffirm.
[Brundle] They're giving
absolutely no quarter.
No benefit to their teammate at all.
They're pushing as if
they're trying to win a Grand Prix.
[Croft] But this is the battle
for last place. remember?
And what a brawl it is.
Let's go. kid. Bring it.
What is this guy doing? Let me through.
[crowd cheering]
[spectators gasp]
[Croft] Round the final corner.
It's close!
They make contact.
- Both Apex GP cars into the gravel.
- [Sonny grunts]
and Pearce hits the barrier.
[crowd clamoring]
- Ah. no!
- No!
[Brundle] This is mad.
The cardinal sin of motor racing.
- A double DNF.
- [Ruben groans]
Just when it couldn't get any worse
for the black and gold.
- [Peter] That's a tough one. man.
- [mutters. sighing]
[crowd shrieking. booing]
We can't corner.
We're bouncing around the place
like we're on the bloody Tube
and now we think it's cool
to leave wheel guns in the pit box.
Who even was that?
- That was me.
- Of course.
Old man.
You losing your hearing? What was that?
You wanna do this here?
Yeah. I'd love to do this here
in front of the team. right.
The one that you're apparently a part of.
- Okay. You made a mistake. It happens.
- [laughs]
I made a mistake. I love this guy. man.
- Don't worry about it. Jodie.
- Are you even listening to me?
- Not really.
- [Kaspar] No!
Stop.
Joshua is right.
An order is an order.
May I remind you that you report to me?
Cool.
Just don't ask me to give up position.
Sorry. Sorry. guys.
Hold up.
You swan into our garage
like some entitled prick.
- "Swan"?
- Calling us piss poor...
- What's "swan"?
- ...and then you drive like that. Huh?
You said I "swan." What's that mean?
You. You're an arsehole.
You come in like an arsehole. You swan.
So swans are assholes?
You're making the mistake of thinking
that I'm just gonna be some grateful kid
who'll bend a knee to an old-timer.
I climbed a mountain to get here. bro.
Formula 1.
Back home we call that
a participation trophy.
[reporters] Joshua. Joshua! Josh!
[clamoring]
[chuckles] Yeah.
What the hell are you smiling about. man?
Did you win something?
There's 20 other drivers
still out on that track
and you're in here
posing for that nonsense.
Do you think any of them respect us?
Do you?
They need to learn that
no one gets past us without a fight.
No one.
You don't like the way I'm driving?
Beat me. swan.
Hell of a race. huh?
Whoo!
[breathes deeply]
Sorry. I didn't see you. Um... [sighs]
[sighs] You still beating yourself up?
Yeah.
Yeah. I know that one. [chuckles]
Um. thanks for what you said out there.
Just don't do it again. okay?
Makes me look like I need help.
Oh. man. You're right. [sighs] Got it.
Hey. for what it's worth.
don't be shitty to yourself.
There's plenty of people out there
that'll do that for you.
Yeah.
[sighs]
"I'm sorry. Ruben. for demolishing not one
but both of your lovely cars.
For coming back into your life
only to destroy it."
Is this your revenge for Monaco?
Yeah. I waited 30 years
and came all this way
to humiliate myself on global television.
Funny. You think I brought you in
to make my other driver quit?
Listen. he's cocky.
He's arrogant. He's got a lot to learn.
[laughs]
You were cocky. you were arrogant
and you had a lot to learn.
I'm not here to hold anyone's hand.
I'm here to race.
No. you're not. Sonny.
You're here to give me a heart attack.
The board is up my ass
and I have to decide
whether to continue this fiasco
- or pull the plug now.
- You have till the end of the season.
By which time Apex will be worth less
than my shoes!
Sonny! God...
Tell me about Kate.
The car.
I wanna talk to her about the car.
She's the world's first
female tech director of an F1 team.
I mean. that takes balls.
Wow. Is that your line?
She'll see right through it.
It's not a line.
- I'm sorry. Sorry.
- Is she married?
Okay. stay there in that tub of ice
until Budapest.
You don't move.
Hey. Ruben...
We can't get there with this car.
[sighs]
Hey. Hey.
Yeah. sorry. Hi. hi. hi.
What you working on?
I'm working on a new front wing concept.
Trying to pick us up a tenth or so.
Cool. And you can replicate turns?
Lateral airflow?
No. just straight line drag.
But. I mean.
we can calculate it from there.
Okay. what about turbulent air
from a car we're following?
No. not exactly. but--
Track conditions. surface quality.
weather. ambient temps?
[chuckles] I'm sorry. uh. is there
something that you wanted to discuss?
Kate. you read my mind.
So how does one get to be the first female
technical director of an F1 team?
Must take...
dedication and lots of hard work.
- That's your urgent question?
- Hmm? Mm-mmm.
Plenty of people think I don't belong here
and I'm happy to add you to the list
if you're implying
what I... I think you're implying.
As a rule I don't imply stuff.
So you like straight talk?
Straight as an arrow. No sugar.
Everyone thinks Ruben's lost it.
That he is clutching at straws.
They're saying maybe he lost a bet.
- Ran over your dog.
- [chuckles]
They're saying Sonny Hayes
isn't a has-been.
He's a never-was.
Yeah. when I said I like straight talk
I meant me.
From others. I mostly prefer praise.
flattery. hero worship.
at times. straight-up bullshit.
- Is that what Ruben's for?
- [laughs]
Ruben. I love the guy.
Most solid. steadfast--
Said you asked if I was married.
Disloyal. mean. twisted.
bitter. husk of a man.
Mmm. yeah. And he also told me about
a big string of ex-wives and girlfriends.
He said to avoid you like the plague.
Okay... [chuckles] ...let me explain this.
When you're going 200 miles per hour
into Eau Rouge.
it's good to know who's got your back.
And for the record.
in all my years of racing.
I have never ever hit on
the team technical director.
[smacks lips] Well. now that's
a huge weight off my mind.
So what's this urgent question?
Okay.
Red Bull. Ferrari.
Mercedes. Aston. now McLaren
all have us beat on straight line speed.
Our shot is battling in the turns.
I need a way
to chase through the dirty air.
You want me to redesign
so you can follow closer?
We need to build our car for combat.
Uh. how am I supposed to make that safe?
Who said anything about safe?
That's your question?
Yeah.
And here's the straight talk.
It's urgent.
[scoffs]
You know.
I bet when you look in the mirror.
you see this rough-and-tumble.
old school. no bullshit cowboy.
Doesn't take orders.
Goes his own way. Huh?
A lone wolf.
Well. I have news for you.
Formula 1 is a team sport. It always was.
And maybe that's why you failed at it?
The only question here is.
"Why did Sonny Hayes come back to F1?"
Now that question
is extremely fucking urgent.
I'll start listening to you
when you finish a race.
[grumbles]
[electronic pop song playing]
♪ Don't let me down ♪
♪ Oh yeah. oh yeah. oh yeah ♪
♪ Don't let me drown ♪
♪ Don't let me down ♪
♪ Oh yeah. oh yeah. oh yeah ♪
♪ Don't let me drown ♪
[song continues]
♪ Don't let me down ♪
♪ Don't let me drown ♪
♪ Nights like these ♪
♪ There's something mystical
About nights like these ♪
♪ And the concept of time don't matter ♪
[song fades]
[brakes hiss]
[Buxton] At the Spanish Grand Prix.
the American rookie Sonny Hayes
had just signed a new contract.
and his future looked very bright.
He'd earned a reputation
for his aggressive driving style.
Seen by some as reckless.
it nevertheless served him well
as he climbed up the order
over the course of the season.
relentlessly pursuing
his first F1 victory.
Hayes was running well
in the opening laps.
chasing down race leader Ayrton Senna.
However when Hayes made a risky move
and attacked Senna on the outside of
a high-speed right-hand turn.
a frightening scene unfolded
as quick as a flash.
[commentator 1] My goodness!
I just saw him plunge off to the right.
There you can see the debris on the right.
What on earth happened there.
I don't know.
[commentator 2]
Yes. this looks very severe indeed.
I must say. it looks like. uh. he is...
he really needs help.
There is nobody coming to him
at the moment.
The race has been stopped.
The red flag is out.
This looks a little bit like a--
[Kate] Our models predict all teams
are gonna be targeting a one-stop race.
Plan A is to switch from mediums to hards.
between lap 27 and 33.
Plan B will be medium-hard-medium.
first window 16 to 21. second. 45 to 51.
Plan C for softs doesn't make sense.
At this temp.
the tire deg will be too high.
Nothing else?
- Yep.
- Yeah. Joshua?
So. we've just got to
drive our race. all right?
Let's not try and be heroes.
Just make it through
those first turns clean.
Can't win at lap one.
starting at the back.
so we just gotta hope for some
lucky breaks later on. all right?
- [crew member] Yeah.
- Yeah.
Create your own breaks.
Um. hello. hi? I just said that.
Hope is not a strategy.
Anything else. Professor?
Um... [sighs]
Drive fast?
- [crowd cheering]
- [timer beeps]
[timer stops]
[Croft] It's lights out. and away we go.
Great start from Hamilton.
Verstappen battling with him.
Piastri. Zhou. Leclerc...
and here come the two Apex GPs.
But Gasly shuts the door.
leaving them with nowhere to go.
Into turn one.
and there's three cars gone off.
Gasly. Ocon. and the AlphaTauri. Tsunoda.
[Sonny] Hit debris. Check my tires.
Yeah. you've got a puncture. Right rear.
Box. Box this lap.
First goddamn turn. A ruined race.
[Sonny] Oh. shit. shit. shit. Ah. shit.
He's coming in! Let's go.
[Sonny] Let's go Plan C.
No. Plan C is for soft tires.
They won't last ten laps in this heat. No.
That's a negative. Sonny. Plan A.
[Sonny] Plan A is called Plan A 'cause
it's when everything is going right.
You see anything going right?
Plan C. Softs.
It's not his call.
Tell him A. as in "asshole."
Okay. let's go! Turn 'em out! Hard tires.
[Sonny] Softs. goddamn it.
- What's wrong with the car?
- The guy sitting in it.
Are you insane? We need hard tires.
Everybody here is at a one-stop race.
[Sonny] We do what
everybody does. we lose.
- Make him go!
- How?
You think I don't know my tires?
I was a mechanic.
Five championship titles
with my bare freaking hands!
Give him his tires.
- [Hugh] Okay. let's go.
- Go. go. change!
Let's go. let's go! Change quick. now!
[Sonny] Be ready.
Ready for what?
- Where's JP sitting?
- [Hugh] Currently running P14.
[Sonny] All right. here we go now.
[Croft] Hayes makes his move.
chasing Kevin Magnussen.
It's a late lunge!
[Brundle] He's damaged his front wing.
Any driver knows Magnussen will shut
the door on a clumsy move like that.
[Sonny] Aw. dagnabbit.
Plan C for "chaos."
[chuckles]
[Croft] So that will bring out a
safety car. which always shakes up a race.
Slows down the leaders.
leaves the field bunched up together.
and gives teams
the chance for a quick pit stop.
which only costs half the usual time.
[Joshua] Safety car. We're boxing. right?
Standby. Kate.
shouldn't we take advantage
while the safety car window is open?
It's early. We gain track position
if we stay out.
[Rico] Stay out. stay out.
Want you out. Push. push. Joshua.
[Brundle] So. the midfield moves up
for the moment.
including Joshua Pearce to P12.
[Joshua] This guy better not
be messing up my race.
Where's JP now?
Currently running P12.
Okay. Plan C. Be ready.
He's gonna do it again.
[Croft] Back marker Hayes
is now down a lap.
He has to let Bottas pass.
or face a five-second penalty.
[Brundle] Hayes is making it
very difficult for Bottas.
Under the rules he has to let him through
before passing three blue flags.
or risk a penalty.
Hey. I'm just putting it out there.
but. uh. maybe you should drive.
[Hugh] Sonny. you've gotten the blue flag.
Let Bottas through.
[Sonny] Come on. now. Little closer.
[Hugh] Sonny. do you copy?
[Sonny] I hear ya. Lettin' him through.
Whoops. my bad.
[Croft] And that's his front wing again!
Oh. that's gonna bring out
another safety car.
Given that each wing
costs more than £200.000.
I think the team might want
Sonny to start chipping in there.
[chuckles]
[Joshua] Guys. it's another free stop.
Please tell me we're boxing.
[Rico] Uh. we're checking.
- Keep him out.
- Stay out. Stay out. You are staying out.
[Croft] More drivers come in
to take fresh tires.
but still. Joshua Pearce remains on track.
He's moved up to P11.
Look who's back.
I know. I know. Be ready.
What is he doing?
I think he's trying to score us a point.
[Sonny] Tell JP to save his tires.
Joshua. just take care of
your tires. okay?
You have to make them last.
[Joshua] Last? No shit. I will be.
[Brundle] With four laps to go
in this stop-and-go race.
thanks to Sonny Hayes.
the driver helped most is his teammate.
now in tenth.
With a 12-second gap ahead of Stroll.
Tell JP to maintain that gap.
Keep pushing.
[Joshua] My tires are gone. man.
What are you waiting for?
Copy that. We have to call it.
He's losing over a second every lap.
Stand by.
[Croft] Into turn two. Hayes battles with
the Williams and pushes it wide.
Seriously. what are we waiting for?
[Croft] Sonny's off the track.
He's gone too far over. [groans]
And that's gonna cause damage.
- Plan C.
- [laughs]
Oopsie. Sorry. guys.
[Croft] That's the third safety car
involving the Apex GP driver.
bringing the Hungarian Grand Prix
to an absolute crawl.
A sub three-second stop.
and he'll keep P10.
Box. Joshua. Box. box. box.
[Joshua] Copy. Coming in.
What did you say?
[Brundle] Joshua Pearce
finally gets to pit.
[Croft] And with a quick stop here.
he could stay in the top ten.
[grunts]
[Brundle] This is critical.
Pearce must beat Stroll to the
pit exit line to maintain tenth place.
[Croft] And he's done it!
With yellow flags out. all the cars
are forced to hold track position.
- meaning that thanks to Sonny Hayes...
- [Joshua] Let's go!
- ...the race ends under a safety car.
- Yeah!
- Vegas!
- What? Whoa!
Hey. yeah. Fuck you. [laughs]
Yeah! [laughs. grunts]
Yes. baby!
[crowd cheering]
[Joshua chuckles] You're crazy. bro.
[Sonny] It's just tenth.
What are you smiling about?
[Croft] And behind our podium placings.
Hamilton and Piastri
complete the top five.
- and Joshua Pearce in tenth...
- Wow.
- ...scoring Expensify Apex GP...
- Yeah. baby.
...their first ever point.
Did you see me? Crazy. right?
- [Sonny] A deal's a deal. I finished.
- Yeah. in last place.
Sounds great when you say it.
[interviewer] I know you have to go
see the stewards later.
what do you think they're
gonna make of your race today?
Well. I have to admit.
you guys got this one right.
- I'm. like... Thank you. Thank you.
- Good job. Yeah.
I'm still a bit rusty and. you know.
finding my way with this car.
but I'm confident we'll get there.
A rope-a-dope at Silverstone.
a demolition derby here in Hungary...
You've been banned from casinos.
Are you trying to get banned from F1?
Take the whole team down with you?
Tell you what. Don.
what do you say we make a bet?
Your £10 against my 10 grand.
We place at Monza. I win your 10.
We don't. you win mine.
- [scoffs]
- Let's do this. man.
Put your money where your mouth is.
What the hell? I'll take that.
- Thank you.
- Thank you so much.
Hey. No more press.
No. Sonny. you don't wanna make
the media your enemy.
And you'll be fined.
Take it out of my paycheck.
We don't pay you enough.
You know. I have to say.
I kinda like it.
It's very sort of punk rock for the brand.
[Peter sighs]
[Ruben] Hmm.
Let's run it again.
How long's he been in there?
All day. Playing with different
tire pressures. ride heights.
What were his times?
He found half a second.
Give me the same setup as him.
[typing]
It must be late. I'm seeing double.
[Kate chuckles]
A deal's a deal.
I'm building her for combat.
At the Dutch Grand Prix.
you'll be entering the Tarzan Corner
at 322 kilometers per hour.
Yeah. Too late to change my mind?
- Yeah.
- [chuckles]
To answer your question.
I was in aerospace at Lockheed
when Ruben came in and...
He liked my work. liked my attitude.
and he sold me on the thrill of fighting
to the death for a tenth of a second.
Traveling the world. the roar of a crowd...
So. I ran the idea past my husband.
Who swiftly became my ex-husband.
Good night.
[line ringing]
[Ruben] Do you know what time it is?
All right.
Tell me about the kid.
Okay. here's another one my dad would say.
"Slow is smooth. smooth is fast."
For what it's worth. One more time around?
- Just one? Come on. Is that all?
- [Sonny chuckles]
- [grunts]
- I'd never live with myself.
if I can't keep up with you. Mr. 1990s.
- [chuckles]
- Let's go!
Joining us today.
we have Kaspar Smolinski.
Zak Brown and Fred Vasseur.
Now. Kaspar. can we start with you.
after what was a fantastic result
- for the team in Hungary last time out...
- Thank you.
...but Sonny has got you skirting the line
of penalties and violations.
Is this your only strategy.
and have you got any spare parts left
in the factory?
[audience chuckling]
We compete like everybody else.
Race models change.
We must adapt. huh?
Well. Zak. can we bring you in on this?
Because you've faced Hayes before.
you know the gray areas in which he works.
Certainly do. Uh. first of all.
he's a lot grayer now.
- [audience chuckles]
- And. uh. we keep tabs on him.
you know. back there behind us.
- [audience chuckles]
- And Fred. any concerns from Ferrari?
What does Ferrari think of Apex?
- We don't.
- [audience chuckling]
["Hold Me" playing]
[fans clamoring] Sonny! You're the best!
[Kate] A better qualifying yesterday
gets us in the thick of things.
P10. P15. [inhales sharply]
So we're gonna go for a two stop.
Medium-hard-medium. that's plan A.
Final stint. we go hards for plan B.
So. on this.
do you have any track concerns?
Don't look at me. Look at him.
It's good for JP.
Start me on hards.
Nah. the track's cooled down.
You won't have any grip.
That's right.
For three weeks.
all the talk's been how reckless I am.
Everyone's wondering
if I'm gonna drive 'em off track.
which means no one's
gonna be watching out for him.
Today. you win us this race.
[Croft] Twenty laps down here at Monza.
and the pack have been split.
The leaders are pulling away.
led by Max Verstappen.
with Joshua Pearce back in P10.
[Brundle] Meanwhile. Sonny Hayes
is holding up the rest of the pack.
stuck behind him in a DRS train.
[Croft] Pearce looks to be in
a great position to finish in the top ten.
and maybe even a run to the podium.
[Brundle] But there's still a long way
to go in this race.
and with rain potentially forecast.
anything can happen.
Tires are gone. Coming in.
Yeah. copy. Box. Box.
[Croft] Apex GP is prepping
a fresh set of tires for Hayes.
That's gonna bring in
all the other teams to avoid the undercut.
Uh. changed my mind.
[Croft] But. no! He's staying out.
with the cars behind him all scrambling
to get on fresh tires that apparently
he doesn't think he needs anymore.
Should we just do the opposite
of what he tells us to do?
Stand by till I lose my tires.
- I thought he had lost his tires.
- [stammers] I think he means literally.
Puncture. left rear. Coming in.
[Croft] And there goes Hayes's tires.
[Brundle] That's quite a mess.
gravel on the track.
That will bring out the virtual safety car
for a quick sweep.
[Croft] So the race gets neutralized.
Everyone slows down
to 40% of their racing speed.
and all the race strategies
will get a reset.
[Brundle] And that is why this is
the perfect time to take a pit stop.
While you're in the pit lane.
your opponents
are restricted to a much slower pace
and you're not going to lose
as much track position when you rejoin.
- I take it I'm staying out. right?
- Copy. Joshua. stay out. Stay out.
- We want you out to gain track position.
- Copy.
Up is down. down is up.
[Croft] Sonny Hayes hesitated
before he left his pit box.
and he's come out just in front
of Max Verstappen.
[Max] That was naughty.
[Brundle] Hayes has slowed a bit
in the pit lane.
which will cost the Red Bull
and the two Ferraris precious time.
Push. Joshua. Push.
You are now P4. P4.
[Croft] Who's coming up from behind?
Here he is. Joshua Pearce.
- Let's see! Let's go!
- Yes!
- This is all playing into his hands...
- Wow.
...at the moment.
Could be a dream afternoon.
But can Hayes hold Verstappen
for a little bit longer?
Verstappen tries into turn one.
nothing doing there.
Gets the better exit.
Through the Curva Grande we go.
- Damn. he's good.
- Verstappen's trying to get past.
[Brundle] Sonny Hayes
looking carefully in his mirrors.
He must let Max Verstappen through.
Yeah. I deserved that.
[Brundle] And Max shows his disapproval.
and I don't blame him. as they head down
towards the second chicane.
[Croft]
And through goes Joshua Pearce in P4.
now much closer to the front of the pack.
[thunder rumbles]
[Brundle] Just seven laps to go.
and here comes the rain.
[Croft] Let's see who plays it safe
with a switch to the intermediate tire.
and who might gamble
to stay out on slicks.
It's getting tricky out here. guys.
What's the plan?
You're running P4. We think P2 and P3
are switching to inters for safety.
and it looks like P1 is staying out.
- What do you wanna do?
- What's Sonny gonna do?
Take a wild guess.
- [Joshua] I'm staying out.
- Copy that.
[Brundle] And the two Ferraris
come in for intermediate tires.
Let's see who else
decides to play it safe.
[Croft] And as George Russell pits.
Joshua Pearce moves into P2.
[cheering]
Sonny. Joshua is staying out on slicks.
If he can hold on and find a dry line.
he's gonna finish second.
Second's not enough.
Damn it.
Okay. coming in for inters.
- Inters. inters.
- Let's go! He's coming in!
- How far behind me are they?
- Thirty seconds.
Oh. my God.
He's gonna take out Verstappen.
Let me know
when they hit the main straight.
Don't tell him! They penalize both cars.
They will take the win away.
Just trust me. will ya?
I'm pushing but I can't catch him.
[Brundle] As the race leaders
approach the main straight.
Sonny Hayes is in another standoff
over team strategy.
- Now.
- No!
[Croft] Finally.
Hayes back out onto the track.
and just in front of Verstappen.
Now he'll get a blue flag here
so Verstappen can get past.
but until then. the Dutch driver
is caught up in Hayes's dirty air.
[Brundle] With every turn he hangs on.
he slows Verstappen
a fraction of a second.
providing Joshua Pearce
one last chance to catch up.
I can see him. I'm almost there.
Tell JP to follow me.
- Copy. Uh. Joshua. Sonny is your tow.
- I'm right behind him.
[Croft] Verstappen pulls away then.
But now. onto the rear wing
of his teammate's car
comes Joshua Pearce.
[Brundle] Pearce picks up
the slipstream from Hayes.
gaining time.
but driving blind in the spray.
Come on. Stay with me. Stay with me now.
Pass. Pass.
- Overtake him. Overtake.
- Copy.
[Croft] He's been gaining. and boom!
Joshua Pearce slingshots past Sonny Hayes.
- and now is in striking distance of P1.
- [cheering]
Tell JP to wait for the straight
into turn one.
Be patient.
- Straight at turn one.
- [crew member] Copy.
Joshua. Sonny says wait for the straight.
The straight into turn one.
[Joshua] I'm right there.
I've got him.
[Brundle] Pearce is right on the gearbox
of Verstappen.
down the back straight
at over 200 miles an hour.
I see an opening. Going for it.
[Brundle] The rookie attacks in 11.
No. no!
[Croft]
Pearce pulls alongside the Red Bull.
he's wheels ahead.
for the first time ever...
Apex GP... Oh. no!
No!
- [sad music playing]
- [no audible dialogue]
[monitor beeping]
[reporter speaking Italian on television]
[sighs]
[sighs. in English] For God's sake.
- [Ruben] Bernadette. how's he doing?
- [Bernadette grunts]
He's stable.
He's resting now.
[exhales heavily. mutters]
Very happy to hear it.
I'm so sorry for what happened.
It was clearly--
Sonny. over here. please.
[sighing]
Um. I just wanna say I've been--
Joshua says you're an asshole.
Yeah. that tracks.
I think you're a dangerous asshole.
- Ms. Pearce--
- You're part of the same team. right?
Looking out for each other.
Except you had him
doing something so dangerous
it almost got him killed.
- Okay. listen--
- No. you listen to me.
This is my son.
And if anything...
anything else happens to him.
I'm coming after you.
And you better pray I don't put you
in a bed next to Joshua
for a very. very long time.
Clear?
Sure.
[sighs]
[reporters murmuring. clamoring]
Sonny. Sonny.
Do you think Joshua blames you
for what happened in Monza?
- [reporters clamoring]
- [reporter] Sonny. come on.
It was clear
that you were running his race.
Look. you kept him out on slick tires.
in dangerous conditions.
that even if you told him not to pass.
wasn't the accident inevitable?
- If I may. If I may.
- [reporters clamoring]
Joshua's back home. recovering.
We are expecting his return
in a few weeks.
Until that moment. our reserve driver.
Luca Cortez right there. will drive and...
- Next man up.
- [clamoring] Answer the question!
[Buxton] A chaotic week
for Expensify Apex GP.
and again. it's Sonny Hayes at the center.
Many are blaming him for his teammate's
horrific accident at Monza.
His high-stakes. gambling style of racing
has the whole grid on edge.
and while the controversy continues
over who was to blame.
doctors have said that Pearce
will miss the next three races.
due to the burns suffered on his hands
as he begins his road to recovery.
[Kate] Today. we're going
with our combat upgrade.
The revised shapes will improve
the flow field under the floor.
allowing us to run in dirty air
with minimal loss of performance.
Means we have to keep the field close
at all times.
and as for this week's plan C...
They've docked us to the back of the grid
'cause they don't like the way we drive.
Fine. Fuck 'em.
'Cause if we can pick up
a tenth of a second from you.
and from you. and you. and me...
If everyone in this room
can make one critical contribution.
that's a second every lap.
And after 72 laps. that's the difference
between last and first.
Plan C...
Plan C's for combat.
Combat. combat. combat.
[crew chanting] Combat. combat.
combat. combat.
[chanting continues]
[driving electronic song playing]
♪ I don't wanna lose my mind
I don't wanna lose myself ♪
♪ Tell me if I crossed a line
I ain't trying to hurt myself ♪
♪ Didn't want to call your name
Only got myself to blame ♪
♪ Oh. yeah ♪
♪ In my world. in my mind
Always running out of time ♪
[crowd cheering]
[Croft] And that's Hayes
in the upgraded Apex.
Now the team were penalized
back to last place after Monza.
but here he is. coming from the cellar.
passing his new teammate. Luca Cortez.
♪ ...still I wait for you ♪
[vocalizes]
♪ Yeah. it feels... ♪
[Croft] Round the banking.
Hayes has got past Ocon.
This is brilliant last lap drama.
What a fantastic finish.
[laughs]
[exclaims. chuckles]
♪ Ain't no way to tell
Which way it's gonna go ♪
♪ But it feels ♪
♪ So good I might just lose my mind ♪
♪ No question if it's wrong or right ♪
♪ And now it's too late
No way to take it slow ♪
[Brundle] Another fearless attack
from Hayes.
And here's where the Apex GP
has found strength.
Three-tenths gained every lap.
and in the corners alone.
♪ I don't wanna lose my mind
I don't wanna lose myself ♪
[Croft] Scrapping away on the last lap.
Sonny Hayes gets the inside line.
but he can't quite get past.
George Russell will hang on here
for sixth place.
but this is Apex GP's best ever finish.
- It's a valiant seventh.
- Combat. I love it!
[crowd cheering]
[manager] Every race you miss.
fans just forget you.
Sonny always seems to be one step ahead.
You never know.
Sonny may be a saboteur. Josh.
He may be a saboteur.
- [crowd cheering]
- [song continues]
♪ Yeah it feels ♪
♪ So good I might just lose my mind ♪
♪ No question if it's wrong or right ♪
[Croft] ...and they go wheel to wheel.
Verstappen and Leclerc.
Verstappen will have the inside.
Perez goes round the outside.
Perez makes contact with Charles Leclerc
as Sonny Hayes threads that Apex GP car
through the midfield.
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Bounce back
When the bottles is on me ♪
♪ I'm pushin' a new pen
Rewriting the story ♪
♪ Hello to my old ways
Goodbye to the nosebleeds ♪
♪ You fighting to stay here
You probably OD'ing ♪
♪ Ain't finna pop for no reason ♪
♪ I don't throw shots. I run legions ♪
♪ I been goin' over the top
Where no queen been ♪
♪ Die with with no regrets
This is my season ♪
[Croft] Talk about leaving it late.
Hayes squeezes through on the inside.
and with a run to the line now.
for their best position ever. P5.
[Brundle] Give the design team a bonus.
because the upgrade
has completely changed this car.
[Croft] And if Joshua Pearce is watching.
well. he must be thinking.
"What might have been?"
♪ Yeah. it feels ♪
♪ So good I might just lose my mind ♪
He's treating you like a pawn. Josh.
- Be a knight! Be a knight! Be a knight!
- [bicycle bell ringing]
[Croft]
Who would have believed this weeks ago?
Expensify Apex GP
has the racing world on notice.
[crowd chanting] Apex! Apex! Apex!
[chanting continues]
[Brundle] Someone call the 1990s.
Sonny Hayes. if you missed him. he's back.
[song ends]
Last one up buys breakfast. [chuckles]
[indistinct chattering]
Look who's back.
[crew cheering. applauding]
Hello.
Good to have you back. JP. We missed you.
[dramatic rap song playing]
♪ This for the underdogs
This for the underdogs. underdogs ♪
♪ Slide out the garage
I got a hundred cars ♪
♪ This for the underdogs ♪
♪ The teller just ask me
How I want the cashy ♪
[crowd chanting] Apex! Apex! Apex! Apex!
♪ I told 'em a hundred large ♪
♪ I want them gold wraps
Put it up double R ♪
♪ Tell 'em get out the way
4x4 big Phantom. supe ♪
♪ They thought I was canceled
I piped up and flipped the channel ♪
[Croft] It's lights out and away we go!
And it's a decent start.
and everyone keeping it clean
as into La Source we go.
Ferrari ahead of Red Bull.
but here the two Apex GP cars
looking to work together as a team.
It's a welcome back to the track
for Joshua Pearce.
and Sonny Hayes glad to see him.
as they slice their way
through positions four and five.
And onto the Kemmel Straight we go.
Now approaching top speed.
Sonny Hayes ahead of Joshua Pearce.
He's showing no ill effects
from that time off after the crash.
The car's working beautifully.
They're working as a team.
But hang on. Pearce right on his tail.
using the slipstream.
Is he about to try and overtake?
Into the chicane we go
and they touch wheels!
- This is disaster for Apex...
- [exclaiming]
...as out goes Sonny Hayes
and into the gravel!
Assholes! [grunts]
[Brundle]
What is happening with this team?
Their first race back together.
and they've run into each other.
- You did great. Joshua.
- Well done. mate.
[laughs]
Whoo! [grunts]
You pull that shit again.
I will knock your teeth out.
Oh. no one gets past us
without a fight. right?
Oh. is this funny?
You think you got a seat next year?
'Cause you just cut your chances in half.
- That's how dumb you are.
- You failed. You failed!
- Why should I listen to you anyway. man?
- Hey.
[exhales heavily]
Look. man.
I don't give two shits about you.
You wanna sabotage your career.
you go right ahead.
I've seen hundreds of guys
with your talent come and go.
No one cares!
But you sabotage Ruben. who backed you?
You sabotage his team?
I won't let you do it.
- Thanks. coach. [laughs]
- Get your shit together!
So stupid! God...
[interviewer]
How would you sum up your race today?
Ooh. Um. it was good.
You know. the car feels great.
I think the team's done an amazing job.
It's just a shame
about the contact with Sonny.
You hate to see that happen.
[pants]
[sighs]
- [Joshua] Hey. how are you doing?
- [host] Hi. how are you?
Good. Sensational.
- Where's the team?
- Right this way. gentlemen.
[sighs]
Brilliant. you made it. Come on. Sit down.
Sonny. you know Joshua.
Joshua. Sonny.
So I'm sure you both
have heard the rumors. [sighs]
We all lose our jobs
if you can't pull off a miracle.
and that's starting with
staying on the bloody track.
Well. we were doing just fine
while JP was out.
I was out because I was listening to you.
- Ish.
- And please don't call me JP.
It's a nickname. You don't get to choose.
And your name doesn't even make sense.
Is it Sonny. is it Hayesie?
- We don't know. do we. Kate?
- [scoffs]
- [chuckles]
- [Kate] Lads.
Have I not delivered you a car?
So you can do one thing for me.
Cards.
Come on. I know you have 'em with ya.
It's my team meeting.
we're gonna do it my way.
- We're playing poker.
- [Joshua scoffs] Come on.
Yeah. Whoever wins gets to be
our number one driver tomorrow.
and if I win. I get to choose.
- Didn't he gamble for a living?
- Mm-hmm. yeah.
Now he's living in a van.
[chuckles]
Texas Hold'em?
["Just Cool" playing]
[Sonny speaks indistinctly]
So. Sonny here likes straight talk.
- [chuckles]
- Isn't that right. Sonny?
- [Sonny] Yeah. that's what I hear.
- [Kate] So. let's talk.
Who wants to go first?
- I'll go first.
No. I'll go first.
What's the difference between
Joshua Pearce and Sonny Hayes?
A lot of decades.
- Hard-won experience.
- Of living in a van?
Total freedom.
Total failure.
Says the guy who still lives with his mom.
Says the guy with two pair.
- Says the guy with trips.
- Says the guy with a full house.
- Girl.
- [Joshua scoffs]
Wait. I don't even live with my mum.
Okay.
She just cooks for me sometimes.
Mm-hmm.
If you'd any constructive criticism
for each other. what would it be?
- Don't be such an arsehole.
- Don't be such a dickhead.
That was constructive.
[scoffs]
You have a deficient frontal cortex.
- A what?
- You can't analyze risk.
It's not all your fault.
It's not fully formed yet at your age.
But come the day you learn patience.
- and stop being so immature. thinking--
- Patience.
- Patience is good.
- [Sonny] Patience.
Joshua.
He doesn't care about
what anyone else has to say but himself.
He just comes in and imposes his will
on all of us with no discussion.
He doesn't listen.
I'm trying. but he doesn't listen.
Mmm.
- Sonny?
- What?
[Joshua scoffs]
[sighs] Wow. [scoffs]
[sighs]
♪ Why they lie to the people?
Why the world is so evil? ♪
[no audible dialogue]
♪ Why cant just cool?
Just let me cool ♪
♪ Walking explosives
Stressing all of the time ♪
Who taught you how to play?
My dad liked to gamble.
- He make big bets too?
- Put a big one on me.
How old were you when your fathers died?
Sorry.
- Thirteen.
Huh.
Why do you race?
Money... [sighs]
...fame and free clothes. [chuckles]
Oh. my God. with the phone.
Put the thing down. will ya?
What do you care what they say?
Easy for you to say. They all love you.
It's just noise. man.
Drive the car.
You're really good at it.
You might be great.
♪ Hyperbolic catastrophic scatterbrain ♪
♪ This is one diabolic catatonic parade ♪
♪ Everyone just go away
There's nothing new to celebrate ♪
[Kate exhales heavily]
♪ There's nowhere left to run away ♪
♪ They're closing off the open seas
They're locking off the runways ♪
♪ They keep telling me the one thing
So far from everything I see ♪
♪ Just go away ♪
[groans] Yeah. [chuckles]
Look at that. huh?
Number one driver tomorrow.
- Bonding?
- [Joshua] Ooh.
Well. this is nice.
We gotta go. mate. Sponsor party at OMNIA.
Gotta steal ya.
Uh. Uncle Sonny.
you're welcome to come with--
Thank you. I'm good.
I have a race tomorrow.
- Cool. Kate?
- No. thank you.
- [manager] Come on.
- Thanks for this. Kate.
[manager] Come on. boy.
Uh... Uh. girls. you might have to...
We're gonna go dancing.
Should we go dancing?
- Yeah!
- [all clamoring]
[romantic pop song playing on speakers]
Listen.
let's get this straight. okay?
I don't mess around during the season.
and never with a member of my team.
and what I'm attracted to is winning.
And you just lost to a pair of fives.
♪ So. baby. let's get messy
Let's get all the way undone ♪
♪ Come over. undress me
Just like I've never been touched ♪
♪ Baby. I'm obsessed with you
And there's no replica ♪
♪ Baby. let's get messy
Let's get all the way undone ♪
[song continues as club remix]
[energetic pop song plays]
♪ I wanna let my hair down
While I'm staring down your face ♪
♪ Wanna go till lights out
Take you right back to my place ♪
♪ You out your mind
If you don't know what this is ♪
Hey.
You're a driver. aren't you?
- Yeah.
- Which team?
Apex GP.
Can you introduce me to Carlos Sainz?
I'll go get him.
♪ Move from the back ♪
♪ Eyes on me
How you like that ♪
♪ Just like this
Here for the night ♪
Oh. hey. Hey.
Oi. why do they say this place is weird?
I like this. bruv.
Glad you're having fun. man.
Be safe. I'm gonna leave. yeah?
- Huh?
- I said I'm gonna cut.
- Oh. wait. no. no. no. You just got here!
- I just... I'm not feeling it.
What do you mean?
We just got here. bruv. Josh!
♪ Just keep watching ♪
[car engine whirring]
- [tires screech]
- [thuds]
[screaming]
[gasps. panting]
[sighs]
Hey.
- [chuckles]
- [groans]
I shouldn't drink tequila.
Last night was Ruben's idea?
[stammers] Yeah. the first part.
- Well... [stammers. chuckles]
- Not the second! [chuckles]
Come on.
Why are you here. Sonny. huh?
Not much of a story.
Okay.
I'm here to prove everyone wrong.
My ex. my old boss.
my first-year uni physics professor--
- That bastard.
- Yeah.
[chuckles]
And until we win. I haven't.
So. unfortunately. I now rely on you.
Mmm.
I was gonna be world champion.
The best there ever was.
I'm just a kid and I'm on the track
with my idols.
Senna. Mansell. Prost.
And I am quick.
I'm fearless.
I was next.
And then...
[clicks fingers]
...it was all taken away.
The crash. huh?
So I lost my seat. my money.
my sanity. my...
myself. really.
Just became this angry.
resentful shithead.
[chuckles]
Not someone I'm particularly proud of.
Till one day.
I realized what I had really lost.
and it wasn't the titles.
or the trophies. or the records.
It was my love for racing.
So I started driving.
Didn't matter the car. the circuit.
didn't need anyone to watch.
Just as long as I was behind the wheel.
I was good.
Sometimes...
[sighs]
What? Come on.
It's rare. but sometimes.
there's this moment in the car
where everything goes quiet.
my heartbeat slows.
it's peaceful.
and I can see everything. and no one...
no one can touch me.
And I am chasing that moment
every time I get in the car.
I don't know when I'll find it again.
but. man. I want to.
[chuckles] I want to.
'Cause in that moment. I'm flying.
[doorbell rings]
Kate.
- Ruben.
- Where is he?
Where's who?
What are you talking about?
Ruben. seriously?
[scoffs] One. how dare you?
Two. I respect professional boundaries.
And three...
Three. yeah. he's on... he's on the balcony.
[grunts]
- Well. you're up early.
- [Ruben] Get dressed.
- Yeah. what's going on?
- They're coming for our car.
[race director] It's my duty to inform you
that we've received an anonymous tip
that your upgraded floor is in violation.
[Ruben] From who?
- I can't say.
- Ah. [chuckles]
Sir. we submitted the drawings long ago.
- Right?
- Mm-hmm.
And you approved them all.
It's whether the parts you're racing with
were developed outside of your facility.
What? That's insane.
Based on the paperwork we've received.
there are concerns.
Hang on. where'd you get these?
These are internal documents.
[Ruben] This team
doesn't break any rules. sir. No. no.
- I'll take that with a pinch of salt.
- Someone can fabricate documents.
Your car's under review.
- You know the procedure.
- What?
You cannot race unless you substitute
the previously approved components.
- No!
- Do you mean our old design?
A shit box!
[in Spanish] No lo puedo creer.
[in English] Where were you
the last two years? Why now?
Because we might actually win a race?
Is that it?
This is not car racing. sir.
this is like corporate espionage!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Come... Come here.
I'm talking to you! Sir!
Without the upgrade. we're screwed.
[Kaspar] Sonny. let it go.
Focus on a clean start.
We'll never win clean.
Can we just not break any rules?
Yeah. the rules are always
against us though. aren't they?
Get them safe through lap one. [sighs]
[Hugh] Sonny. we just need
to keep it in one piece. Okay?
[Sonny breathing shakily]
[tense music playing]
Sonny?
[tires squeal]
- Oi. what the hell?
- I don't know!
[Joshua] What's wrong with Sonny?
Joshua. yep. Keep focused.
You're still good.
What's he doing?
He's driving angry.
Not good. It's not good.
Sonny. we need to make these tires last.
Take it easy.
No. he's put the car in qualifying mode.
He's gonna run the battery down.
Tell him to put it back.
[Hugh] Sonny. you're in qualifying mode.
What's going on?
Sonny. what's happening?
[Croft] ...blasting along
Las Vegas Boulevard. 210 miles an hour.
Hard on the brakes now.
and into the chicane.
Sergio Perez. ahead of Sonny Hayes.
but that's a mega exit from Hayes.
He's gotta gain on Sergio Perez.
and he's closing.
Meter by meter. Inch by inch.
Is this the place to take a gamble?
Hayes attacks round the outside.
[crowd gasping. clamoring]
No! No!
[somber orchestral music playing]
Why do we do this?
What's wrong with tennis. huh?
- Or golf.
- [chuckles]
[chuckles] Right?
[exhales heavily]
Christ.
We are totally insane.
[sighs]
"C5 neck fracture.
Spinal contusion.
Compressed thoracic vertebrae.
Further blunt force impact trauma
likely to result in vision loss.
paralysis. death."
Really lead with the good news.
don't they?
This is a report from 30 years ago.
Why didn't you tell me?
You never should have raced again. Sonny.
How... How do you think I'd feel
if you die on the track?
Revenge for Monaco.
[stammers] It's not a joke!
It's me who's liable. Sonny.
And don't think there's some
bullshit loophole to get you out of this.
- No.
- Ruben. we're drivers.
We are not drivers. not anymore.
I'm sorry. We're not.
We're losers.
We're a pair of dumb.
sentimental.
broke losers.
[sighs]
Okay. You're off the team.
[sighs] Your van is in the garage
with all your stuff in it. and...
[chuckles]
I never should have pulled you
into this. Sonny.
I'm sorry.
Ruben. wait!
[sighs]
I need this.
No one drives forever. Sonny.
Not even you.
Pippa. load up Monza.
Just like it happened. In the rain.
[crew member] Joshua.
Sonny says wait for the straight.
the straight into turn one.
Run it again. please.
[crew member] ...wait for the straight.
the straight into turn one.
Run it again. please.
[crew member] The straight into turn one.
[exclaims] Whoo! [chuckles]
[Peter] Sonny.
Sonny.
Hey. You're not in Abu Dhabi?
I fly out tonight. I. uh...
Yeah. I wanted to catch you.
So. listen. [sighs]
We both know that the board's
wanted to unload Apex from the start.
but. yeah. then you rode into town.
raised our whole profile.
and now I've. uh...
Yeah. I've got... I've got buyers lining up.
- Uh-huh.
- Gotta be honest with you. man.
I thought you were gonna be the...
the final nail in the coffin.
But now I see the play.
And I want you as part of the package.
What sort of package?
I've set up a sale where I run the team.
and keep you on for strategy.
maybe even team principal.
With the money from that deal.
I can make you a very rich man.
Here's the thing.
With the... the changing regulations.
new Mercedes power unit.
Kate's aero. two new drivers...
we've got a real shot
at the championship next year.
What about Ruben?
Don't worry.
You know.
We won't embarrass him.
We'll keep him on with a... with a title.
or brand ambassador...
You know. something.
And I get final say?
Don't change a thing.
Do what you do. man.
And that's the irony here.
You know. the board
originally approved your hire
because we thought you'd help us lose.
- Sorry to make you sweat.
- Hey.
That's my number.
Talk to your people.
But. uh... [chuckles] ...right after the race.
I. uh... I wanna lock down the deal. okay?
- So. by Sunday?
- Perfect.
Listen. this thing can be your legacy.
you know?
An F1 champion.
What you always wanted. right?
It was you who forged those documents.
wasn't it?
Huh.
[chuckles]
- You're a killer. man. aren't you?
- Hey. I'm a winner.
- Aren't you. huh?
- [sighs]
Okay.
Oh. hey. How's the back?
Better.
I've got an amazing guy.
I'll. uh... I'll hook you up.
Hail Mary.
You good?
[sighs] Listen. Mum.
I've gotta tell you something.
In Monza. right before the crash.
it was my decision to make the move.
Sonny actually told me to wait.
[breathes deeply]
[knocks on door]
Family.
I've been working the phones with IndyCar.
and I think I can get you
a test drive. bruv.
- Hello. Auntie. [kisses]
- Hi.
They're trying to pull in
a new demographic. obviously.
And the ladies love that smile.
And we can throw in some incentives.
like flights and cars.
Listen. Cash. you can go.
I don't need you today.
Nah. mate. You got media next.
[chuckles] I don't care. They can fine me.
Besides.
that's not why I'm doing it. right?
Josh. starting tomorrow.
we're not "doing it" anywhere.
It's all just noise.
Media. engagement. followers.
Listen. I've gotta focus on the race.
[Cash] Auntie. please.
Well. you heard the man.
- Deal.
- Deal. [chuckles]
- Yo.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Guys. what's happening?
Parc fermé.
Waiting for FIA to cut the seals.
Oh. good. [sighs]
- We got time then.
- For what?
For...
[chuckles]
No. no. no.
Welcome to the Paddock Club.
for our most valued guests.
Please. uh. grab a drink.
make yourselves at home.
and. uh. enjoy the very best view
there is of. uh... of Formula 1.
Okay? Okay.
[clears throat]
Hey. guys. don't stop! Keep going!
[chuckles]
[sighing]
[groans]
[stirring orchestral music playing]
No way. [chuckles]
[sighs]
Jesús. it's like a morgue around here.
[stammers] How'd you get here?
Premium economy.
[Ruben scoffs]
What? What is this?
Well. that's my bullshit loophole.
Oh. no. forget it.
I'm not even going to read that.
That is a real legal document
from a real Tijuana lawyer...
- [chuckles]
- ...waiving all liability to you
and your company vis-à-vis this race.
myself. and me.
- And...
- [inhales sharply]
...since you owe me my last paycheck.
technically I'm still on this team.
Kate. where's the shitbox?
The FIA confirmed that
the documents were forged.
and they were sent by someone from Apex.
Huh.
Okay. I don't care about your loophole.
I don't.
That is my car. You are not racing it.
- Ruben.
- No. Sonny.
Listen.
I can't let you do that.
I can't.
Okay?
[stammers]
If the last thing I do is drive that car.
I will take that life. man.
A thousand times.
[sighs]
We can't win.
We can't if we don't try.
[sighs]
[laughing]
[laughs]
[groaning]
[knocks on door]
How come you never look at the card?
[Sonny] What card?
[chuckles]
[crowd cheering]
Welcome to the very final spots
on the grid.
And as ever. we'll go from last to first.
And breaking news here in P22.
because we're hearing
the Apex GP team have made...
- Hey. Peter.
- Yeah?
That's your guy. Isn't it?
...being replaced by Sonny Hayes. who
didn't even make the trip to Abu Dhabi...
Uh. will you excuse me for one second?
I'm really sorry.
Now. the rules require that
he has to start at the back of the pack.
Excuse me. What the hell?
What?
You still got my phone?
[phone buzzes]
- Good luck today.
- You too. James.
Excuse me. Hey. Sonny. Sonny!
Hey. look.
I know we've had our differences.
- but look. this is your last F1 race.
- Chaz! This guy.
Any thought...
What's that?
[crowd cheering]
Bloody hell.
Bloody hell!
[laughs]
[UAE national anthem playing]
Elbows out?
Elbows out.
[Croft] All set for our season finale
here in Abu Dhabi where it's lights out.
And away we go.
Good start there for Joshua Pearce.
Drivers jockeying for position
as we head full-throttle
down the main straight and into turn one.
Tricky first corner. and going wide.
the Aston Martin and the AlphaTauri
- [laughs]
- as Pearce picks up two places.
[Brundle] Yes. Pearce showing
some real maturity there.
He saw a bad situation before it happened
and he's off to a great start.
Don't even think about it.
[Croft] Here comes the Alpine
down the inside. Contact!
And three days out of hospital.
Hayes will feel that.
Gained places. guys. We're alive.
[Brundle]
I hope he hasn't damaged the car.
but despite everything.
it's still a great first lap.
[Croft] It is! Hayes in P16.
Pearce. his teammate. up to P9.
Red Bull. Mercedes and Ferrari
holding on to the lead.
Apex in the midfield.
Let's see if they can do anything
to shake up this race.
Gap to leader?
[Hugh] Fifteen seconds.
Keep JP plus 20 seconds. Plus 20.
- Length of a pit stop.
- You know why.
[Croft] It's a busy race for Sonny Hayes.
and now here comes Kevin Magnussen
looking to make a move.
And this could spell trouble.
[Brundle]
There's history between these two.
Often. the irresistible force
meets the immovable object.
And Magnussen. looking down the inside.
- locks up and hits Hayes.
- Box. box. Box. box. box.
Copy. coming in for hards.
Damn.
Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast.
Here we go. boys.
[Croft] Hayes exit the pits.
He had to come in
because of that damage to his tire.
But what of Joshua Pearce?
Where do Apex GP go with him?
[Joshua] Guys. am I boxing?
What's the plan?
Plan C. Plan C. Stay out. Stay out.
- [laughs] Chaos.
- Copy that.
Joshua slows down the leaders for Sonny.
Sonny does the same for him.
[Brundle] Pearce stays out.
It's a strategy that Apex have used
before this season.
It helps them with track position for now.
but they gotta keep these tires alive.
It's the only way we keep this close.
And then we need luck.
I'm way ahead of ya.
[Rico chuckles]
[Croft] Lap 25. and every driver
so far has pitted. bar one.
And he leads the race.
Joshua Pearce controlling the pace
out in front.
[Brundle] And that gives
his teammate. Hayes.
a chance to maintain
his position in the midfield
despite the contact.
puncture and pit stop.
They're working really well together.
How's JP doing up there?
He's keeping the leaders at bay.
DRS active next straight. Sonny.
Got it.
[Croft] Onto the back straight.
He's enjoying this new upgrade.
and he's got DRS.
and he's got Pierre Gasly.
Sonny Hayes up into P15.
[Hugh] Sonny. you have got the pace.
Keep pushing.
[Brundle] Pearce has been doing
a great job out front
despite the used tires.
but that moment is nearly over now.
Verstappen up the inside and he's through.
[Croft] Fabulous first stint
from Joshua Pearce.
Max has passed.
and his troubles don't end there.
Here comes Charles Leclerc.
It's another overtake.
Pearce lost the lead and drops now to P3.
Sorry. guys. My rear tires are shot.
Copy that. Box. JP. Box. box.
[Brundle] Pearce stretching those tires
to the limit.
Short-term pain for long-term gain.
And he exits the pit.
He'll have fresher tires.
He can now attack
in the second half of the race.
Sonny. the three leaders
are still on hards.
They're gonna have to stop again.
This is their pit window.
One of the leaders is gonna undercut.
I need to be there when they do.
P3 Ferrari. Pippa. can he beat it to one?
[Pippa] Depends on their stop.
[Croft] Will the undercut
work for Ferrari?
Five point eight.
He needs to pick up half a second.
Sonny. you need half a second.
Go. go. go. go. go.
[Croft] And Sonny Hayes is on the charge.
Under the track goes the Ferrari.
Through the first corner goes Sonny Hayes.
It's neck and neck. It's really tight.
Sonny Hayes is just ahead of Carlos Sainz.
- Yes! Come on!
- [Croft] It's worked so far for Apex GP.
But their trouble's not over.
Down the inside. there's a chance
for Carlos Sainz. and he takes it.
But he locks up.
The Ferrari goes wide
and Sonny Hayes says.
"Thank you very much indeed."
How are they staying so close to the lead?
Uh. they're. um... They're working together.
[Brundle] Two Apex cars in the top 10.
but still a long way to go.
[Croft] Twenty laps remaining. and Apex
has worked their way up the order.
We're now at the final pit stop window.
This is our chance for P1.
Make sure JP beats them out.
[Croft] Hamilton and Leclerc
come into the pits. but Pearce stays out.
- [Joshua] Talk to me. Can I catch 'em?
- Yep. They're just coming out.
Push now. Push now. Push. push.
Copy. Pushing.
[Croft] Oh. this is gonna be close.
Joshua Pearce inching ahead.
Staying ahead.
For the second time in this race.
he leads.
[laughs] Let's go!
- [grunts]
- [grunts] Yes.
You are P1. Joshua. [laughs]
[Brundle] But Pearce will have
a hard time holding them off
with Hamilton and Leclerc on fresh tires.
[Croft] Four laps to go.
Sonny Hayes is in P4.
He's five seconds behind his teammate.
but both are on old tires.
There's little chance
they'll gain any places now.
And here's Hamilton
attacking Pearce into turn five.
And he's through.
Nobody has to stop again
and our tires are nine laps older.
[Brundle] And Leclerc attacks and passes.
Pearce's tires are absolutely finished.
There was nothing he could do about that.
I'm sorry. guys. I've got nothing left.
[Croft] It's been the Apex GP story
all year long.
Plenty of risks.
A great underdog story.
but we know. Martin.
only talent crowns a champion.
[Sonny] Losing grip. Tires are gone.
[Brundle] Yeah. Sadly. the deck's
been stacked against them
and now they're out of cards to play.
It ain't over. right?
No. but nothing can change.
It's the worst feeling in the world.
George Russell on the attack.
Hayes looking to defend.
through the left-hander they go...
And there's contact!
Hayes is spun round and into the barrier.
That's a big one.
[gasping]
- Fucking yes. yes. yes.
- Oh. no.
Yeah. no. Ooh.
[Brundle] There's debris
all over the race track
and substantial damage to the barriers.
The stewards have no choice
but to red flag this race.
Miracle.
[Croft] And speaking of damage. Martin.
Hayes will only be allowed
to continue in this race
if he can get his car
all the way around the circuit
and back to the pit lane.
[Hugh] Sonny. Sonny. can you get it back?
I'll get it back. I'll get it back
if I have to push it back.
Come on. Sonny. Nice and easy.
[grunting]
He's still going.
[chuckling] He's still going.
[crew member] JP. red flag.
Red flag. Come in.
We are still alive. hermano. [laughs]
Red flag!
[Brundle] And somehow Sonny Hayes
has got his car back to the pit lane.
- It's a miracle.
- I know! I know.
Never seen one until now.
Home free. Good girl. Let's go.
New softs. both cars.
Raise the tire pressure
for three quick laps.
- Team. time to build a car.
- [crew cheers. clamors]
[Croft] Red flag rules then.
The teams can make changes.
They can make repairs to their cars.
But only in that pit lane.
And with only ten minutes to make repairs.
Apex GP has their work cut out.
[Brundle] And all cars
can fit a fresh set of tires
for what will be a three-lap sprint.
- Dodge! Dodge. are we gonna make it?
- I don't know. I don't know.
That was clean.
That wasn't me. Not this time.
"Not this time"?
Tell that to the stewards.
Check the replay.
I got this. Lift that corner.
I'm good. I'm good. I'm good. I'm good.
[Brundle] What the stewards
will be looking at
is whether Hayes went off completely
or kept at least one tire on track
during the contact with Russell.
- Yo. you good?
- Yeah. good.
Listen. you were on track.
Yeah. it was your corner.
P3 and P4. Let's go!
[Croft] Given Hayes's reputation. they'll
be looking at this really. really closely.
I'm not expecting a quick decision.
Come on. that's clearly a penalty.
Like... I mean.
not that that's what we want.
but. like. objectively. that's the guy.
- Oh. man. It can't end this way.
- It's just a time-out.
Like the last 30 years.
It's in the hands of the racing gods now.
We gotta believe. Gotta believe.
[Croft] Plenty going on here in the pit.
Oh. look. Here comes the new wing.
This is a massive job.
Yeah. but will the car hold together
for the remaining three laps?
Well. that barrier looks okay now.
The marshals just sweeping
the last few bits of debris off the track.
and the clock continues to tick down.
[Brundle] Yeah. it's just over two minutes
until this race gets underway again.
JP. JP!
Three laps.
Three laps is a lifetime.
Go win this thing.
Hey. Sonny. Sonny. you got a minute?
We got you a car.
Ah. you rock. Thank you.
[Brundle] Because Apex GP
didn't make the top 10 in qualifying.
they have a new set
of soft tires available.
which will give them extra speed
over the cars ahead of them
on the used soft tires.
This red flag is a lifeline.
You'd almost wonder
if Sonny didn't engineer it.
But wait. we're the only cars
on fresh tires
because we sucked in qualifying yesterday?
Never got the chance to use them.
Sometimes when you lose. you win.
- That don't make no sense.
- It's a Sonny thing.
[Croft] Light at the end of the pit lane
is green.
We're off on our second formation lap
of the evening.
and when this race resumes.
this is gonna be an epic sprint.
Hamilton. Leclerc. Pearce. Hayes.
That's the top four.
[Hugh] Sonny. we just heard
from the stewards.
Goddamn it. Now?
[Hugh] We're debating whether to tell you.
Kaspar says. "Yes."
but Kate says. "Don't."
- She says you're fast when you're angry.
- [chuckles]
- Tell her. "Job well done."
- [laughs]
[Croft] And here's news.
Stewards have made their decision.
That Lap 55 collision between Hayes
and Russell is ruled a racing incident.
- No further investigation.
- [cheering]
Whoa! Sonny.
That was your line. Sonny.
Go finish your race.
Joshua. we still got two cars in the mix.
Then we've got a team.
[Brundle] Once those red lights go out.
this will be an absolute sprint
to the finish.
Position advantage to Mercedes
and Ferrari.
Tire advantage to Apex GP.
Tell JP to follow my lead.
[crew member]
Joshua. Sonny says to follow him.
Follow? He's behind me.
- Cheeky bastard.
- [Sonny] That's it. Stay with me.
[crew member] He's giving you a tow.
Take it.
All the way.
Come on. kid. Get it. Come on!
[Croft] Hayes plays the decoy.
and Pearce rockets past Leclerc
and up into second.
And Leclerc's in danger from Sonny Hayes.
Round the outside. he's up into P3.
[Brundle] Perfect teamwork.
Hayes and Pearce working together.
it's like racing ballet.
[Croft] It's a beautiful sight.
but now their sights are set on
the race leader. Lewis Hamilton.
Yeah! Remember me?
Come on. boys. Send it!
Why didn't they overtake?
Lewis will defend
whichever car attacks first.
- But they both can't wait.
- Someone has to sacrifice.
[Croft] Two onto one.
and all the pressure is on Lewis Hamilton
as Apex work as a pack.
Go win it. kid.
Hayes makes the first move.
- Hamilton defends. Pearce attacks.
- Yeah!
- And Pearce has P1.
- [crowd cheering]
- Yes!
- Yes. yes!
[Croft] Toe-to-toe. wheel-to-wheel.
this is epic racing
to finish off the season.
And Sonny Hayes and Lewis Hamilton
aren't done yet.
Hamilton. on Sonny Hayes.
- There's contact!
- [crowd clamors]
And through goes Hamilton.
- Yes. yes!
- Come on!
Yes!
Guys. talk to me.
Where's Sonny? Can he finish?
[crew member] One more lap. JP.
Hamilton never backs down.
Can Sonny finish the race. man?
[crew member] Yes. he's on track.
Just watch Lewis when he fights.
You're P1. No more risks.
No such thing.
[Croft] The rookie holds his line.
He won't back down.
He's here to fight
the seven-time world champion.
That made contact.
The leader and Lewis Hamilton
are out of this race.
[Brundle] Despite yellow flags flying
at turn one. this race will continue.
[Hugh] Sonny. push. push. push.
You're P1! You're P1!
[Brundle] Apex GP has only one lap to go.
The question is do they have the car?
We have the driver.
[muffled] Yeah! Go on. Sonny!
[breathing heavily]
What's happening?
He's flying.
[Hugh] Sonny. you did it! We won! We won!
[crew cheering]
Yeah!
Yes!
[cheers]
We won!
- Yeah!
- [cheering continues]
Yeah!
We won!
- We did it! Whoo!
- Oh. my God. Oh. my God.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
- Come on! Yes!
- Yes!
Means another three years
for Ruben. right?
Yeah.
I guess we'll check back about that deal.
Presuming you're still on the board.
[Croft] Breathtaking!
Breathless! Incredible!
What an Abu Dhabi Grand Prix
this has been!
What a victory as well!
[Brundle] Absolutely. It's a race
for the ages. An absolute thriller.
- And this man wins his first Grand Prix.
- Well done.
- It's been 30 years in the making.
- Well done!
And the team did a brilliant job
from the pit wall.
- And of course we can't forget Pearce...
- Oi! What you smiling about?
- ...playing his part in this victory.
- [Sonny] You.
I'm gonna win a million races.
You should at least have one.
[Sonny laughing]
We did it.
[Sonny] Yeah. we did.
[exclaims]
Whoo!
[sighs]
[spectator] Sonny!
No. no. no. no. Give it to him.
No. no. no. Give it to him.
Oh. my God. Thank you. Thank you.
[cheering]
Let's go!
[mutters]
[kisses] I love you.
Yeah!
Today we get to say...
- "We are the best in the world!"
[cheering]
[cheering continues]
[dramatic music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[cheering]
Joshua.
If you were ever to consider
to drive somewhere else.
you know where to find me.
Thanks. Toto. but I'm happy where I am.
Congratulations.
Yeah. baby! Let them wait!
- Let them wait!
- [laughs]
- [exclaims]
- [screams]
[Ruben] The cup!
Kate. you built a hell of a car.
[chuckles]
- [crowd exclaiming. chattering]
- [breathing heavily]
[sighs]
[panting]
[chuckles]
[Kate] Another race I don't know about?
Somewhere.
That beats this? [chuckles]
Yeah.
I wanted to say. "See you down the road."
but in a way that was more poetic.
So...
Can I see you down the road?
Yes.
[chuckles]
Hang on to that until then.
Okay. [chuckles]
And drive fast.
[Sonny chuckles]
[Joshua] And where do you
think you're going?
[chuckles] Don't worry about me.
Go celebrate.
But you're off to where?
You know. couple more dragons to slay.
It's your team now.
It was always my team.
[both chuckle]
I'll be watching.
See you around. swan.
[laughs]
[dramatic music playing]
[sighs]
[music stops]
["Hablando de Mí" playing on radio]
[engine revving]
Hello!
[in Spanish] Buenas.
I'm told you're looking for a driver.
What's your name?
Sonny Hayes.
Have you ever driven Baja?
Nope.
We can't pay much.
Not about the money.
So what is it about?
[chuckles]
[rock music playing]
♪ Hey ♪
[engine revving]
♪ Flying through the city
With the speakers up loud ♪
♪ Speeding by with the top down ♪
♪ Fast lane living
Till they put me in the ground ♪
♪ And I don't wanna stop now ♪
♪ Pull away. wind blowing
Now I'm cruising ♪
♪ Put the past in the past
A new day is coming ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. we can ride ♪
♪ Four wheels. you and I
Gotta get out of here ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. my savior ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. we can fly ♪
♪ Out of this burning fire
Just take me anywhere ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. my savior ♪
♪ Pedal down and drive ♪
♪ Drive ♪
♪ Pedal down and ♪
♪ Just drive ♪
♪ Out of the city
Now we're switching four lanes ♪
♪ Got our eyes on a fresh start ♪
♪ The world as we knew it
That was caught up in flames ♪
♪ Get ready for the next part ♪
♪ You know I'm good
If I'm back in the gutter ♪
♪ 'Cause this life
It was never about the money ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. we can ride ♪
♪ Four wheels. you and I
Gotta get out of here ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. my savior ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. we can fly ♪
♪ Out of this. good and far
Just take me anywhere ♪
♪ Ha-la-lay-la. my savior ♪
♪ Pedal down and drive ♪
♪ Drive ♪
♪ Pedal down and ♪
♪ Just drive ♪
♪ Drive ♪
♪ Pedal down and drive ♪
[song ends]